* [CONTACT USPlease send all letters to the editor, manuscripts, promotional materials, and subscription questions to Editors@TheOccidentalObserver.net.](https://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/contact-us/ "Contact Us")

### We Respect Your Privacy

Any personal information you provide to us, including and similar to: your name, address, telephone number and email address, will not be released, sold, or rented to any entities or individuals outside the core administrators of this site.

### Credit Card Details

_The Occidental Observer_ has several options for donations (see donate page) for all of our monthly or one-time donation transactions. Credit card and billing information is always handled on the 3rd-party processor server only — never here on TheOccidentalObserver.net — please check their policies for any privacy terms you need to be aware of.

### WordPress CMS

By default WordPress does not collect any personal data about visitors, and only collects the data shown on the User Profile screen from registered users. However some plugins may collect personal data. By default WordPress does not collect any analytics data. However, many web hosting accounts collect some anonymous analytics data. By default WordPress does not share any personal data with anyone. Our content servers and systems are all located inside the U.S. except for the cloud-based nameservers used for security which uses cloudservers in many places to detect attacks on the site. Security is all compliant with European data protection law which requires data about European residents which is transferred outside the European Union to be safeguarded to the same standards as if the data were in Europe. They have all contracts in place to safeguard all data of everyone who visits the site. We do not have access to those items or any collected data beyond basic analytics and speed data.

When visitors leave comments on this site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection and email address entered by you (not displayed publicly). If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. Comments are mass-deleted on a regular basis which removes all data completely from the entire system.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you created an account there for your uploaded avatar image. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These cookies are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year unless you remove them from your browsers and temporary web files.

### External Sites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites most likely collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. We are not responsible for the content of the many external web sites linked within our pages. You are advised to read the privacy policy of external sites before disclosing any personal information.

### Cookies

A “cookie” is a small text file that is placed in your browser which allows our site to recognize you each time you visit. Cookies themselves do not contain any personal information and are only used to enhance and personalize your experience while browsing our web site.

This site uses Google Analytics for site-wide statistics. You may opt out of their data storage (we’ve added the top software in order for you to do that), even though there is no recognizable data to us. We have never opted in to their regulated deeper analytics as we only use them to keep the site repaired and know if anyone is really visiting us. They gather IP addresses, browser type/app/operating system, etc., as all sites do which have statistics. We have looked at the data collected that is shown to us in their control panel, and nothing we see there identifies you personally. www.policies.google.com/technologies/cookies/ is where you will find all Analytics privacy information.

This site uses Jetpack by Automattic (WordPress) to handle our post and comment subscriptions so they retain the data you enter there yourself. Please contact us after you unsubscribe if you wish to verify your name/email data has been deleted from subscriptions. If you use an email address that is associated with Automattic’s (WordPress) Gravatar.com site, then it will show in the back end and if you leave a comment. We suggest you don’t use that email if don’t wish your image to show. People forget that. www.Automattic.com’s Privacy Policy will tell you all about what they collect (most of which only PHP programmers know). Visitor comments are checked through an automated spam detection service provided by WordPress/Automattic, Akismet. Data is pooled there to mitigate spam. Akismet collects information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect depends on how the User sets up Akismet for the Site, but typically includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

This site uses a cloud-based DDOS attack protection system to assist on site speed, security, traffic mitigation, and general stats. They collect a great deal of data, but no personal information or identification. In order to be a security company, they have data and use it in ways we’ll never know. There is no way to avoid this service as they are the nameservers of the site itself (DNS).

### Remember The Risks Whenever You Use The Internet

While we do our very best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you might provide or is picked up from your browser for site stats (as even banks, credit agencies, insurance companies, government agencies and departments are broken into constantly) and you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords or other account information. In addition, other web sites or services that may be accessible through our web site have separate data and privacy practices, independent of us, and therefore we disclaim any responsibility or liability for their policies or actions or losses.

There are security computer/device programs, such as Kaspersky Ultimate (has high ratings), that are able to guide you through setting up your browser(s) to match what you really want — then protect those settings quite aggressively.

Please contact those vendors and others directly if you have any questions about their privacy policies. Contact us for anything related to just this site, which does not use anything additional to present the site via WordPress.

Search-engine how to configure your browser (there are many) for the “privacy” that you would like to have. www.Youtube.com has instructional, short videos on How-To.

Finally, we reserve the right to change our privacy policy at any time (like everyone). We encourage you to check this page occasionally for the most current information. If you have any questions, concerns or suggestions about our privacy policy, please contact support at theoccidentalobserver dot net.

If you continue to use this site, you give consent to this Privacy Policy.  

Rev. 2 on 7/11/2018

### Fróði Midjord and Kevin MacDonald on the Chauvin Trial and the Great Replacement

Find Us On Social Media:  

### Keep Up-To-Date By Email

Subscribe below to get our latest posts in your inbox twice a week.

Name  

Email  

### Watch TOO Video Picks

### DONATE

### Follow us on Facebook

### Topics

Topics Select Category Affirmative Action/Minority Preferences  (25) Africans and African Americans  (67) Africans and African Americans  (23) AltRight  (15) Americanism  (2) Anders Breivik  (14) Anti-Defamation League  (32) Anti-Jewish Writing  (59) Anti-Semitism  (90) Anti-White Attitudes  (71) Arts and Clture and Politics  (30) Bias in Academia  (20) British Politics  (76) Catholic Church  (30) Christian Zionism  (10) Christianity  (31) Comment  (1) Communism  (6) Conservatism  (11) Costs of Multiculturalism  (100) Cultural Marxism  (8) Decline of Whites  (40) Donald Trump  (43) Dual loyalty  (9) Egalitarianism  (1) Elena Kagan  (9) Ethnic Genetic Interests  (16) Ethnocentrism  (20) EU Migration  (13) Eugenics  (9) European Invasion  (14) European Nationalism  (75) European New Right  (11) Evolutionary Psychology  (68) Fascism  (10) Featured Articles  (3,000) Free Speech  (24) General  (836) Historical Anti-Jewish Writing  (9) Holocaust Industry  (8) Homosexuality  (6) Immigration  (79) Implicit Whiteness  (24) Individualism/Collectivism  (2) Islamization  (17) Israel  (38) Israel Lobby  (90) Jewish Academic Activism  (12) Jewish Aggressiveness  (7) Jewish Attitudes  (19) Jewish Attitudes on Free Speech  (24) Jewish Double Standards on Immigration and Multiculturalism in Israel vs. the Diaspora  (66) Jewish Ethics  (9) Jewish Ethnic Networking  (48) Jewish Ethnocentrism  (39) Jewish Genetic Segregation  (13) Jewish Identity  (1) Jewish Influence  (100) Jewish Influence in France  (20) Jewish Intelligence  (8) Jewish Journalism  (5) Jewish Loyalty  (11) Jewish Moral Particularism  (6) Jewish Opposition to Free Speech  (9) Jewish Religiosity  (10) Jewish Self-deception  (44) Jewish Support for Multiculturalism  (65) Jewish Traits  (6) Jewish Wealth  (6) Jewish Writing on Anti-Semitism  (34) Jews and Gun Control  (2) Jews and Hollywood  (28) Jews and the Left  (90) Jews and the Right  (3) Jews as a Hostile Elite  (62) Jews as An Elite  (57) Jews in Economy/Finance  (46) Latinos  (17) Liberal Bias in Academia  (12) Liberalism  (18) Libertarianism  (15) Mainstream Conservatives  (37) Masculinity  (1) Media Bias  (85) Media Images of Whites  (8) Media Influence  (44) Mesirah  (2) Moral Ingroups  (6) Multiculturalism  (7) Muslim Immigration  (48) National Socialism  (1) Neoconservatism  (58) Netherlands  (1) Origins  (1) Orthodox and Hasidic Jews  (4) Pathological Altruism among Whites  (8) Philo-Semitism  (7) Pleas for Support  (12) Policing the Media  (17) Political Correctness  (37) Political Processes  (6) Population Genetics: Jewish  (8) Protestantism  (3) Race  (6) Race Differences in Behavior  (28) Racial Differences  (4) Racial Zionism  (6) Racialization of American Politics  (42) Refugees  (1) Repression of Dissidents in the West  (2) Russia  (2) Satire  (5) Satire and Ridicule  (2) South Africa  (9) SPLC  (33) The Arts and Culture  (57) The Charge of White Racism  (16) The Law  (12) The Left  (16) The Occidental Quarterly  (10) Thinking Racially  (1) TOO Site  (2) TOQLive  (2) Traditional American Culture  (3) Translations: Czech  (6) Translations: Finnish  (4) Translations: French  (57) Translations: German  (23) Translations: Greek  (1) Translations: Italian  (23) Translations: Japanese  (3) Translations: Polish  (1) Translations: Portuguese  (46) Translations: Romanian  (2) Translations: Romanian  (5) Translations: Russian  (1) Translations: Spanish  (7) Translations: Swedish  (7) Trump  (5) Unite the Right  (3) Universalism  (2) Video Archive  (175) Western Civilization  (61) Western Culture  (169) White Anger  (23) White Pathology/Guilt  (89) White Racial Consciousness and Advocacy  (177) White Racial Consciousness and Advocacy  (113) White Victimization  (36) White Working Class  (8)

### Authors

Select Author... A. W. MacCrinnan (2) Adam Komiaga (7) Aesop (1) AFP Staff (1) Ahmad Al Khaled (1) Alain DeBenoist (18) Albemarle Man (6) Alberto Buela (1) Ales Nemec (3) Alex Fontana (2) Alexander Dugin (11) Alexander Jacob (26) Alexander Middleton (1) Alexander Mikhaylov (7) Alma Rauhaus (1) Amalric de Droevig (4) Ambrose Kane (2) American Krogan (2) Anatole (2) Andrew R Gladwell (1) Andrew Joyce, Ph.D. (273) Andrew Lowden (1) Andy Nowicki (1) Ann Coulter (145) Anonymous (5) Anthony Hilton (8) Anthony Hilton and Kevin MacDonald (3) Antonius Aquinas (2) Antonius J. Patrick (2) Armor (5) Austen Layard, Ph.D. (2) Beau Albrecht (2) Benjamin Villaroel (5) Bernard M. Smith (17) Bob Wallace (2) Brad Griffin (1) Brent Mason (1) Brenton Sanderson (102) Brian Hess (3) Bryan Christopher Sawyer (7) C. J. Miller (1) Camillus (1) Carolina Hartley (2) Caryl Johnston (1) Cat McGuire (2) César Keller (1) César Tort (3) Chad Crowley (3) Charles Dodgson (17) Charles Jansen (2) Chauke Stephan Filho. (11) Chris Downie (2) Chris Roberts (1) Chris Woltermann (1) Christian Johanson (3) Christian Miller (7) Christophe Dolbeau (5) Christopher Donovan (84) Christopher Martin (1) Civilta Americana (1) Civus Non Nequissimus (1) Colin Liddell (41) Connor Mitchell (1) Cooper Sterling (24) Courtney from Alabama (1) D. F. Mulder (1) D. H. Corax (4) Dan Michaels (19) Daniel Barge (3) Daniel Höglund (2) Daniel N. Davidson (1) David Boyajian (1) David Yorkshire (1) Desmond Walker (1) Diversity Chronicle (2) Douglas Watson (1) Dr. Lasha Darkmoon (32) Dr. Virginia Abernethy (1) Duke Dougherty (1) Duns Scotus (1) E. Furlong (1) E.R.E. Knutsson (9) Earl P. Holt III (1) Edmund Connelly, Ph. D. (114) Edward Dutton (23) Edward von Newhouser (1) Elizabeth Whitcombe (5) Emil Kirkegaard (2) Enza Ferreri (13) Eric Kunnap (6) Eric Paulson (2) Esther Watcher (2) F. de Boer (2) F. Roger Devlin and Stephen J. Rosse (1) F. Roger Devlin, Ph.D. (39) Ferdinand Bardamu (16) Ferryn Laws (1) Flavia (1) Francis Carr Begbie (81) Francis Goumain (12) Frank Weisse (1) Frederick Talmadge (1) Free Expression Foundation (4) Freeman (4) Ganainm (12) General Nick Zeljko Glasnovic (1) Georg Immanuel Nagel (1) George F. Held (7) Gilbert Cavanaugh (5) Giles Corey (12) Gleb Selivanov (3) Glen Allen, Esq. (10) Greg Johnson (10) Greg Klein (2) Gregoire Canlorbe (4) Gregory Conte (7) Gregory Hood (1) Gregory Ritter (1) Guide to Kulchur (1) Guillaume Durocher (133) Gunnar Alfredsson (2) Hadding Scott (11) Hans Holtzcamp (1) Harald E. Brandt (1) Harrison Elings (1) Henry St. John (5) Hewitt E. Moore (10) Horus (11) Howe Abbot-Hiss (1) Howe Abbott-Hiss (7) Hubert Collins (11) Hugh Moriarty (2) Ian David Carlyle (1) Igor Artemov (3) J. J. (1) Jacek Szela (4) Jack Antonio (1) Jack Beauregard (3) Jack Sen (8) Jack Spence (3) James Andrewes (4) James Edwards (49) James Joseph Sanchez (1) James Miller (1) James Murray (5) James O'Meara (1) James Roberts (1) James Wald (10) Jared Taylor (2) Jason Cannon (17) Jessica Reavis (1) Jim Goad (1) Jimmie Moglia (2) Johannes Scharf (1) John Adams Leland (1) John Friend (1) John Graham (25) John Graham and Kevin MacDonald (1) John Highlands (1) John Horst (1) John Lilburne (3) John Moffat (1) John Q. Publius (30) John Rand (1) John Schretenthaler (3) John T. Kelly (1) Jonas De Geer (3) Jonathan Pyle (2) Jonathan Sawyer (6) Joseph Jordan and Glen Allen, Esq (1) Joseph Pryce (3) Josephus Tiberius (2) Juleigh Howard-Hobson (2) K R Bolton (1) Karl Haemers (29) Karl Nemmersdorf (15) Karla Friedrich (1) Kevan S (1) Kevin DeAnna (1) Kevin Lamb (4) Kevin MacDonald (1587) Kevin MacDonald (1) Koki Murata (3) KosChertified (8) L. Scott Smith (3) Lara Johnstone (2) Laurent Guyenot (1) Lawrence Murray (3) Lawson Wellborn (1) Lee Miller (1) Lipton Matthews (6) Liv Heide (1) Lucian Tudor (1) Luke (1) Luke Wolfe (1) Lute Currie (1) Lydia and Peter Brimelow (1) M. Jaggers (17) Marcek\` Bas (1) Marco de Wit (1) Marcus Alethia, Ph.D. (6) Marcus Apostate (2) Margaret Pyke (1) Mark Brahmin (2) Mark Green (3) Mark Gullick (22) Mark Westerman (1) Marshall Yeats (13) Martin Webster (8) Matt Parrott (20) Matthew Francis Decker (1) Matthew Raphael Johnson (1) Matthew Roberts (1) Max West (2) Mel Smith (1) Merlin Miller (2) Merlin Miller and Adrian Krieg (1) Michael O'Meara (1) Michael Robeson (1) Michael Ryan (1) Morgan Jones (1) Neil Kumar (3) Nelson Rosit (31) Neovictorian (1) Nick Griffin (4) Nick Kollerstrom (1) Nigel Jackson (2) Nils Wegner (1) Oliver Williams (3) Olof Karlsson (1) Pat Buchanan (42) Patrick Cleburne (4) Patrick Cloutier (1) Patrick McDermott (4) Patrick Slattery Ph.D. (3) Paul Angel (2) Paul Dachslager (1) Pavlo Khomenko (6) Pedro de Alvarado (1) Penelope Thornton (5) Peter Baggins and Kevin MacDonald (4) Peter Baggins, Ph.D. (18) Peter Brimelow (2) Peter D. Bredon (1) Peter Gast (1) Peter Jansen (1) Peter Stuyvesant (33) Pierre de Craon (1) Pierre Simon (6) Povl H. Riis-Knudsen (4) Preston Wiginton (1) Prof. Andrew Fraser (31) Prof. Ricardo Duchesne (11) Pyotr Antonov (1) R. Houck (8) Ray Charlston (2) Ray Wolters (3) Reginald Thompson (4) Remi Tremblay (1) Richard Knight (22) Richard McCulloch (21) Richard Spencer (3) Richard Storey (1) Richard Thornbourn (2) Rik Storey (1) Rob Isner (1) Rob Winfield (2) Robert Bonomo (1) Robert Henderson (1) Robert S. Griffin, Ph.D. (67) Robert Stark (1) Robert Wallace (1) Robert Woodson (2) RockaBoatus (21) Rolo Slavski (35) Roman Bernard and Richard Spencer (1) Romanized Visigoth (1) Rudyard Kipling (1) Russell James (6) Ryan Andrews (2) Sam Davidson (1) Sam Dickson (13) School of the West (1) Scott Howard (9) Sertorio (1) Sid Secular (5) Sigurd Kristensen (4) Sinclair Jenkins (2) Sir Tristram (10) Sloan Kettering (1) Spencer J. Quinn (18) Stefan H. Vestappen (1) Szilárd Csonthegyi (5) Taylor McClain (3) Ted O'Keefe (1) Ted Sallis (16) Terrence Hill (4) Thaddeus Z. Imas (1) The Irish Savant (12) Theordore Owlglass (1) Thilo Sarrazin (1) Thomas Dalton, Ph.D. (39) Thomas Goodrich (1) Thomas Jones (3) Thomas M. Hines (2) Thor Magnusson (1) Thorborne Richardson (1) Tim Murray (17) Tobias Langdon (337) Tom Kawczynski (1) Tom Oliver (3) Tom Sunic and Alain de Benoist (1) Tom Sunic, Ph.D. (151) Tom Zaja (10) Tony Pivetta (1) TOO Moderator (1) Trevor Lynch (3) Trudie Pert (9) V. S. Solovyev (16) Valdis Bell (1) Virginia Abernethy (1) Warren Balogh (2) Warsaw Sentinel (1) Washington Irving (1) Wayne Northrup (2) White Man Faculty (3) Wilburn Sprayberry (1) Wilhem Wilhem Ivorsson (1) Will Fredericks (2) Will Wright (1) William Davis (5) William H. Regnery II (1) William Sun (1) Winston Smith (4) Xenia Sunic (1) Yggdrasil (1) Zachary Sessions (3) Zula B Law (1)

### Monthly Archives

Monthly Archives Select Month December 2024  (36) November 2024  (76) October 2024  (52) September 2024  (40) August 2024  (42) July 2024  (49) June 2024  (37) May 2024  (46) April 2024  (42) March 2024  (35) February 2024  (29) January 2024  (38) December 2023  (28) November 2023  (35) October 2023  (39) September 2023  (31) August 2023  (26) July 2023  (27) June 2023  (30) May 2023  (30) April 2023  (39) March 2023  (31) February 2023  (28) January 2023  (31) December 2022  (30) November 2022  (28) October 2022  (27) September 2022  (25) August 2022  (30) July 2022  (28) June 2022  (25) May 2022  (29) April 2022  (28) March 2022  (32) February 2022  (22) January 2022  (17) December 2021  (18) November 2021  (20) October 2021  (20) September 2021  (17) August 2021  (18) July 2021  (25) June 2021  (21) May 2021  (21) April 2021  (20) March 2021  (22) February 2021  (16) January 2021  (23) December 2020  (23) November 2020  (18) October 2020  (18) September 2020  (24) August 2020  (20) July 2020  (24) June 2020  (30) May 2020  (20) April 2020  (17) March 2020  (20) February 2020  (23) January 2020  (20) December 2019  (16) November 2019  (22) October 2019  (23) September 2019  (25) August 2019  (20) July 2019  (24) June 2019  (23) May 2019  (19) April 2019  (17) March 2019  (21) February 2019  (22) January 2019  (19) December 2018  (19) November 2018  (20) October 2018  (19) September 2018  (16) August 2018  (20) July 2018  (22) June 2018  (21) May 2018  (17) April 2018  (17) March 2018  (21) February 2018  (17) January 2018  (20) December 2017  (15) November 2017  (17) October 2017  (19) September 2017  (19) August 2017  (19) July 2017  (23) June 2017  (21) May 2017  (16) April 2017  (23) March 2017  (23) February 2017  (31) January 2017  (25) December 2016  (23) November 2016  (27) October 2016  (21) September 2016  (20) August 2016  (22) July 2016  (22) June 2016  (26) May 2016  (32) April 2016  (25) March 2016  (24) February 2016  (23) January 2016  (32) December 2015  (27) November 2015  (29) October 2015  (27) September 2015  (28) August 2015  (28) July 2015  (24) June 2015  (35) May 2015  (31) April 2015  (20) March 2015  (30) February 2015  (29) January 2015  (32) December 2014  (21) November 2014  (21) October 2014  (31) September 2014  (28) August 2014  (26) July 2014  (30) June 2014  (28) May 2014  (35) April 2014  (38) March 2014  (31) February 2014  (24) January 2014  (26) December 2013  (15) November 2013  (18) October 2013  (18) September 2013  (26) August 2013  (16) July 2013  (19) June 2013  (18) May 2013  (19) April 2013  (17) March 2013  (18) February 2013  (19) January 2013  (20) December 2012  (18) November 2012  (14) October 2012  (16) September 2012  (18) August 2012  (16) July 2012  (18) June 2012  (15) May 2012  (19) April 2012  (20) March 2012  (26) February 2012  (16) January 2012  (21) December 2011  (21) November 2011  (22) October 2011  (22) September 2011  (25) August 2011  (32) July 2011  (26) June 2011  (21) May 2011  (27) April 2011  (25) March 2011  (23) February 2011  (23) January 2011  (29) December 2010  (31) November 2010  (24) October 2010  (26) September 2010  (23) August 2010  (34) July 2010  (19) June 2010  (25) May 2010  (30) April 2010  (35) March 2010  (40) February 2010  (43) January 2010  (47) December 2009  (43) November 2009  (7) October 2009  (10) September 2009  (12) August 2009  (13) July 2009  (12) June 2009  (7) May 2009  (9) April 2009  (8) March 2009  (11) February 2009  (6) January 2009  (3) December 2008  (5) November 2008  (8) October 2008  (6) September 2008  (12) August 2008  (10) July 2008  (4) June 2008  (2) May 2008  (10) April 2008  (4) March 2008  (2) February 2008  (8) January 2008  (9) December 2007  (3) October 2007  (2) August 2007  (1) January 2007  (1)

### RECENT TRANSLATIONS

### Blogroll

NEW: Individualism and the Western Liberal Tradition

### Also available at Barnes & Noble

Culture of Critique

### Also available at Barnes & Noble

Separation and Its Discontents

A People That Shall Dwell Alone

© 2024 The Occidental Observer - [powered by Enfold WordPress Theme](https://kriesi.at/)

By continuing to browse the site, you are legally agreeing to our use of cookies and general site statistics plugins.

### Cookie and Privacy Settings

How we use cookies

We may request cookies to be set on your device. We use cookies to let us know when you visit our websites, how you interact with us, to enrich your user experience, and to customize your relationship with our website.

Click on the different category headings to find out more. You can also change some of your preferences. Note that blocking some types of cookies may impact your experience on our websites and the services we are able to offer.

Essential Website Cookies

These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you with services available through our website and to use some of its features.

Because these cookies are strictly necessary to deliver the website, refusing them will have impact how our site functions. You always can block or delete cookies by changing your browser settings and force blocking all cookies on this website. But this will always prompt you to accept/refuse cookies when revisiting our site.

We fully respect if you want to refuse cookies but to avoid asking you again and again kindly allow us to store a cookie for that. You are free to opt out any time or opt in for other cookies to get a better experience. If you refuse cookies we will remove all set cookies in our domain.

We provide you with a list of stored cookies on your computer in our domain so you can check what we stored. Due to security reasons we are not able to show or modify cookies from other domains. You can check these in your browser security settings.

Check to enable permanent hiding of message bar and refuse all cookies if you do not opt in. We need 2 cookies to store this setting. Otherwise you will be prompted again when opening a new browser window or new a tab.

Click to enable/disable essential site cookies.

Other external services

We also use different external services like Google Webfonts, Google Maps, and external Video providers. Since these providers may collect personal data like your IP address we allow you to block them here. Please be aware that this might heavily reduce the functionality and appearance of our site. Changes will take effect once you reload the page.

Google Webfont Settings:

Click to enable/disable Google Webfonts.

Google Map Settings:

Click to enable/disable Google Maps.

Google reCaptcha Settings:

Click to enable/disable Google reCaptcha.

Vimeo and Youtube video embeds:

Click to enable/disable video embeds.

Privacy Policy

You can read about our cookies and privacy settings in detail on our Privacy Policy Page.

[](https://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/donate/) First, a huge THANK YOU to those who have contributed during 2024. I’m not sure you really realize your _support is critical_ to our success and our ability to fulfill our unique niche of providing fact-based, well-written articles on White identity, White interests, Jewish influence, and the deleterious effects of multiculturalism and massive non-White immigration.

As you know, the Dissident Right, including _TOO_ has been widely de-platformed by the likes of PayPal, Patreon, Stripe, Square, and Coinbase (and others), so that mail-in checks (which can be set up with your bank on a recurrent basis) or cryptocurrency are the only options.

Your gifts of **any** amount are welcome. The best (and easiest) way of giving is to subscribe for a recurring monthly amount that works for you by using your bank’s bill-paying feature. Regarding crypto, we accept Bitcoin, Ethereum, Cardano, Litecoin, and Monero.

The page with information on donations is **[here](https://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/donation/)**.

Your support is important for many of our writers, and it’s safe to say that we are now competitive with similar websites in paying them. As always, the financial base for projects like _TOO_ is dwarfed by the financial resources of our enemies. Your support is a huge psychological and financial boost for many.

[](https://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/donate/)Again, the page with how to donate is [**here**](https://www.theoccidentalobserver.net/donation/). This page has been updated to provide greater clarity. There are two sections, the top section for tax deductible donations and the bottom section for non-tax deductible donations respectively.

**[Let me know](mailto:editors@theoccidentalobserver.net)** if any of the instructions are unclear.

Thanks for thinking of _TOO.  
…_ and Merry Christmas!

Kevin MacDonald  
Editor
